Preliminary Inventory to the Charles R. Page Papers, 1907-1938.
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles R. Page Papers,
1907-1938.
68015
Page, Charles R.
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and miscellanea, relating to the work of the U.S. Shipping Board in regulating shipping rates and practices, allocation of ships, recruitment of seamen, and claims for insurance. Includes correspondence with Edward N. Hurley and Joseph Tumulty.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Shipping Board.; Shipping--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Transportation.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; United States--Politics and government.
Container List
- Seven notebooks of daily activities, 1917 October 26 - 1919 May 15. These notebooks were typed by Mr. Page's secretary and give detailed accounts of persons and problems (Box 1., Folder 1)
- Five index books covering the above (Folder 2)
- A weekly report of the minutes of the Board of the Emergency Fleet Corporation, 1919 January 2 - May 14 (Box 2., Folder 1)
- Report of Director, General Charles Piez, to the Trustees of the Emergency Fleet Corporation, 1919 April 30 (Folder 2)
- Photocopies of correspondence regarding Page's resignation as Commissioner of the U.S. Shipping Board (Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, etc., mostly with Edward Hurley (Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Katherine Lawler to Charles Page, 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
- Memorandum outline of notes made during visit to England, Scotland, and France, 1920 January-March (Folder 6)
- Clippings and dinner programs relating to Herbert Hoover's relief work (Folder 7)
- Clippings relating to the Pearl Harbor investigation (Folder 8)